回到谷仓
翻译
零九/presisco
校对
presisco
特效
压制
presisco
既然看起来我别无选择，
As it seems I have no other options,
那我容许自己揭露一部分重要信息
I have conceded to reveal some important information
给你们水晶战士
to you crystal gems.
这...
This...
是地球
...is the earth.
在这个星球的最核心处
At the very center of the planet's core
是融合簇
lies the cluster.
转身
Rotate.
这就是融合簇-一个巨大的人工融合体
This is the cluster -- a massive artificial fusion
由几百万的宝石碎片组成
composed of millions of gem shards.
它已经保持稳定几千年了
It has laid dormant for thousands of years
一直呆在这个星球的地壳中
within this planet's crust.
当这个宝石被激活并形成实体，
When this gem activates and takes its form,
后果会是灾难性的
the result will be catastrophic.
现在！
Now!
那是什么？！
What is that?!
这是融合簇啊
It's the cluster.
它看起来可不像这样
It does not look like that.
但它真实存在，而且可以随时被激活！
But it is real, and it can activate at any moment!
天辣噜
What a cluster.
这个麻烦必须被解决
That abomination must be stopped.
但怎么做？
But how?
我们需要制造某种机器
We'll need to build some sort of machine
携带我们前往地球中心
to take us to the center of the earth.
它必须-
It'll have to --
嘿！
Hey!
我还没说完呢
I wasn't finished speaking.
我们需要做的是制造某种机器
What we need is to build some sort of machine
携带我们前往地球中心
to take us to the center of the earth.
它需要能承受360GPa的压强
It'll need to withstand up to 360 gigapascals of pressure
与9800度的高温
and temperatures of 9,800 degrees.
那么，我们不能再浪费时间了
Well, we mustn't waste time.
我们得立即开始搜寻机器的零件了
We need to start finding parts for this machine immediately.
是的，很明显
Yes, obviously.
我们要不从拆解这个居所内的所有设备开始？
We'll start by dismantling all devices inside this dwelling?
蛤？
Wha?
这个原始的辐射能集聚装置
This primitive radiation concentrator
能派上用场！
should come in handy!
这个原始的震动传递器
This primitive vibration transmitter
很可能有用
could possibly serve a function.
虽然可能性不大
There's a remote chance
但这个原始的图像方块内会有可用的部件
something useful could be inside this primitive image cube.
等等！我有个更好的主意
Wait! I have a better idea
这样我们就不用拆了这间房了
that doesn't involve destroying the house.
典型的史蒂文方案
Classic Steven.
好吧
All right.
谷仓内的东西
What we have here in the barn
应该足以让我们起步了
should be adequate enough for us to get started.
首先，我建议我们通过类型整理元件
First, I recommend we organize the component types
然后基于我们可用的东西制造一个大体蓝图
and assemble a rough blueprint based on what we have available.
对不起，史蒂文
Sorry, Steven.
这是个很可爱的绘画，但实际不会是这样
It's a lovely drawing, but it won't look like this.
嗯...
Hmm.
很好，对，这就够了
Good. Yes, this is adequate.
谢谢，你可以离开了
Thank you. You can go now.
呃，什么？
Uh, what?
嗯？
Hmm?
呃...就这样吧？
Um... That will be all?
你是怎么让她离开的？
How do you get her to leave?
抱歉，我不会走的
Excuse me, I am not leaving.
对啊，她要留下来帮助制造钻头，不是吗？
Yeah, she's got to stay and help build the drill thing, right?
不，不，你没弄清楚
No, no. You're confused.
一个珍珠不可能像这样制造东西的
A Pearl can't build a thing like this.
为什么不？
Why not?
因为珍珠们不是用来干这个的
Because pearls aren't for this.
她们只负责长得好看
They're for standing around a-and looking nice
并，呃，保管你的物品，对吧？
a-and, uh, holding your stuff for you, right?
够了！
That's enough!
如果我们要一起工作的话，
If we're going to work together,
你得听我的
you're going to have to listen to me.
听你的？
Listen to you?
是你教导她这么说话的？
Did you teach her to talk like this?
你在说什么啊？
What are you talking about?
她是个珍珠
She's a Pearl.
她是个天生的侍从
She's a made-to-order servant
就像其他几百个珍珠一样
just like the hundreds of other pearls
被用来在母世界四处炫耀
being around back on homeworld.
等等，有几百个珍珠？
Wait. There's hundreds of pearls?
其实，是的，但-
Well, yes, bu--
而且她看起来也还挺潮啊
and she looks like a fancy one, too.
啊！
Ugh!
几百个珍珠
Hundreds of pearls.
那么，顺便问下，你属于谁呢？
So, who do you belong to, anyway?
没人！
Nobody!
那你存在的意义是什么？
Then what are you for?
其实，你现在可以归我所有啊
Well, you can belong to me for now.
哈！一个拥有珍珠的橄榄石！她们在老家会怎么说呢？
Ha! A Peridot with a Pearl! What would they say back home?
现在，给我听着，你个小矬B
Now, listen here, you little tiny twerp.
提醒一下，你现在可是在我们的地盘上
In case you've forgotten, you're on our turf now,
而我为这个星球的独立打了一千年的仗
and I didn't fight a 1,000-year war for this planet's independence
可不是为了听命于你这样的人！
to take orders from the likes of you!
等下？
Excuse me?
我是个天生的技师和认证的幼儿园运维
I am natural technician and a certified kindergartner.
我生来如此
I was made for this.
你诞生的意义是听从命令，而不是发号施令
You were made to take orders, not to give them.
喔，喔，等下，伙计们！
Whoa, whoa, hang on, guys!
现在，我们都能同意你们两个都擅长制造东西，
Now, we can all agree that you're both good at building things,
那么，你们就不能听一听对方的话吗？
so, can't you just try listening to each other?
不！
No!
我造东西的水平和你一样好，甚至还更高些！
I'm as good at building things as you. Better, even!
哈！说一件你在工程学方面更好的事来！
Ha! Name one thing you could engineer better.
说啊！
Go on.
机器人
Robots.
嗯？
Hmm?
你们该制造机器人-巨型机器人
You should build robots -- giant robots.
我能看到一场比赛-一个巨型机器人比赛
I see a race -- a giant robo-race.
包括奖品-巨型机器人奖品
With prizes -- giant robo-prizes.
你是指类似竞争吗？
You mean like a competition?
对，用来分辨谁更擅长制造东西
Yeah, to see who's better at building stuff.
你说的“机器臀”是什么？
What are these "ro-butts" you speak of?
橄榄石的“机器臀”（ro-butts）致敬卡通网络的动画"Whatever Happened to Robot Jones?"
它们就如同你派遣的时髦的大理石家伙们，
They're like those funky marble guys you were sending,
只是要更为庞大而且你要能操作
only bigger and you can ride them.
哈！制造一个“机器臀”简直易如反掌！
Ha! Building one of these "ro-butts" will be easy!
那么，我则能更快的制造一个！
Well, I can build one faster!
只是你的幻觉而已！
That's what you think!
呦，史蒂文，那些超能学霸们怎么样？哇！
Yo, Steven. How are the wonder nerds doing? Wah!
发-发生了什么？她们是在制造钻头吗？
Wh-what's going on? Are they building the drill?
不，我们现在在制造机器人
No, we're building robots now.
你说的是什么？
What'd you say?
我说...
I said...
巨型机器人！
Giant robot!
哈！真可悲
Ha! Pathetic.
现在，请观看-我眼中的终极力量！
Now, behold my vision of ultimate power!
嘿！
Hey!
我的更高，我赢了
Mine's taller. I win.
珍珠的机器人的设计与理念和《背骑少女》中的两轮机动机器人类似
宝石人们与小姐们，欢迎来到第一届年度机器人奥运会！
Ladies and gentlegems, welcome to the first annual robolympics!
机器人奥运会（Robolympics）致敬卡通网络的动画《我的机器人好朋友》
喔！
Whoo!
爆米花！
Popcorn!
这次比试将测试机器人工程师能力中的
This competition will test our robo-engineers' skills of
机器人制造与机器人操作
robo-construction and robo-piloting.
获胜者将能主导
Whoever wins will get to be in charge of
融合簇钻头之类的东西的制造
building the cluster drill machine thing.
让比赛开始吧！
Let the games begin!
机器人奥运会
喔喔喔喔！
Ohhh!
吼吼吼！
Oh!
橄榄石如此低俗的设计出自卡通网络的动画《坏蛋康卡》第一集的一个场景
紫晶的姿势像不像《泰坦尼克》里的桥段？
嗯？嗯-
Mm-hmm.
主观项目
好吧，伙计们，这是最后一个项目了！
All right, guys. This is the final event!
你能行的，小珍！
You got this, p!
就是干，姐妹！
Get it, girl!
哼！
Hmph!
预备！就位！抛出！
Ready! Set! Chuck!
喔～
Whoa.
你们都赢得了一点
You both get a point on that one.
嗯，嗯
Hmm. Hmm.
看来我们的最终结构是...平局!
Looks like our final score is...A tie!
那么，就这么决定了
Well, that settles it.
你们两个可以一起主导项目了！
You both get to lead the project together!
不！这不算完！
No! This isn't over!
我要求加赛！
I demand we have a tiebreaker!
呃，让我们消停会吧
Ugh, let's just give it a rest.
够了！我们平局了，我们是一样的
That's it! We tied. We are the same.
我们做点别的吧
Let's move on.
不！你是个珍珠
No! You're a Pearl.
你就是比我卑微！
You are beneath me!
我永远都比你强，
I'll always be better than you,
并且今天的所见所闻没一样能改变我的想法！
and nothing I've seen today will ever change that!
那么，你见过一个珍珠做这个嘛？
Well, have you ever seen a Pearl do this?
唔！
Oof!
那么，你想搞事情？
So, you want to fight?
好啊
Good.
我们一开始就该这么做！
We should have done this from the beginning!
停下，巨型机器人不该打架！
Stop! Giant robots shouldn't fight!
撕，撕，撕，撕！
Fight, fight, fight, fight!
哈哈哈！
Ha ha ha!
珍珠！
Pearl!
没什么，汇集们，我能做到
It's all right, guys. I've got this.
小心！
Be careful!
爆她菊！
Kick her in the butt!
这真是毫无意义！
This is pointless!
你没可能打败我的！
There's no way you're gonna beat me!
你只是个物件，某人的闪亮玩具！
You're an accessory, somebody's shiny toy!
你是从哪学的表现得像个独立的宝石人？
Where do you get off acting like your own gem?
你只是个珍珠！
You're just a Pearl!
没错！就是个珍珠，怎么地？
That's right! I ama Pearl!
喔呼！
Whoo-hoo!
你说的也许没错，
What you're saying may be true,
但毫无意义
but it doesn't matter.
因为我仍会收拾你！
I'm still gonna kick your butt!
珍珠的飞踢类似《飞跃巅峰》中的招式
哦！
Oh!
呃哦
Uh-oh.
橄榄石和珍珠看起来太像绿巨人和洛基了
珍珠！
Pearl!
胜利是属于我的！
Victory is mine!
现在我是领导
Now I'm the one in change.
赞我！赞我！
Praise me! Praise me!
橄榄石的致敬《外星入侵者ZIM》中GIR的一个镜头和原话
珍珠，你还好吗？
Pearl, are you okay?
我很好
I'm all right.
好样的，小珍！哦，那真是帅呆了
Yeah, p! Oh, that was awesome.
你真是碉炸天！
You were hard core!
哦，真的？
Oh, really?
喔，没错
Oh, yeah.
嘿！为什么你们不听我呢？
Hey! Why aren't you listening to me?
我赢了！我才是这里天生的领导者
I won! I'm the natural leader here.
她只是个普通的珍珠！
She's just a common Pearl!
你错了！
You're wrong!
如果珍珠真像你说的那样，
If pearls are really like you say they are,
那珍珠一点也不普通！
then Pearl isn't common at all.
她训练自己进行战斗，她学习如何进行制造，
She trained herself to fight, she learned how to build things,
而且她每天都非常努力，超越自我！
and she works hard every day to be greater than she already is!
那并不寻常，那真是棒极了！
That's not common. That's amazing!
来吧，我们一起收拾残局
Come on. Let's clean up this mess.
珍珠，你应该和我摔跤玩的
Pearl you should come wrestling with me.
呃，我不确定
Uh, I don't know.
但-但-但我赢了！
B-b-but I won!
规则呢？
What about the rules?
欢迎来到地球
Welcome to earth.
石榴的话致敬电影《独立日》中威尔·史密斯的原话
我得承认，
I have to admit,
像你这样的珍珠
it's remarkable that a Pearl such as yourself
能成为一名...博学的技师非常了不起
could become such a... Knowledgeable technician.
嗯...我们要不开始吧？
Mm. Why don't we get started?
橄榄石倒拿电钻的姿势与《噬魂师》中Death the kid拿手枪的姿势类似
你拿反了
You're holding it upside down.
没错，显然
Yes. Of course.
你得知道，你机器上的那些原型挂件
You know, those round appendages on your machine
也许会有用的
could be useful for something.
那叫做轮子
They're called wheels.
看来我们总算要开始阻止融合簇了
Looks like we're well on our way to stopping the cluster.
“你们认为自己可以阻止我？”
"You think you can stop me?"
啊！
Aah!
啊！我们完蛋了！
Aah! We're doomed!